A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, RG 6 FA787
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, RG 6
1949-1964
1958-1963
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
United States. Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission
FA787
15.65 Cubic Feet 37 standard document boxes, 3 legal document boxes, 1 standard half document box
Biographical / Historical
In 1958 President Dwight D. Eisenhower selected Laurance Rockefeller to head the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, a fact-finding and advisory group created by Congress. Eight of ORRRC's fifteen members came from Congress and seven were presidential appointees. Their assignment was to determine the outdoor recreation needs of the American people to the year 2000 and recommend policies and programs necessary to assure that the needs will be met. A year later funds were appropriated and the commission set to work.
ORRRC conducted the most comprehensive fact-finding study ever made in this field and the results were published in 27 volumes. The major findings and more than 50 recommendations were contained in ORRRC's own report, Outdoor Recreation for America, submitted to President John F. Kennedy and Congress in 1962. This report presented a five-point program designed to improve and increase recreation use of both public and private land and water resources, to make more effective use of existing recreation areas and to acquire new ones, particularly shoreline. This program spelled out proposals for a national recreation policy; a classification system for outdoor recreation resources; expansion, modification and intensification of existing programs; a Federal Bureau of Outdoor Recreation and a program of grants-in-aid to the states.
The ORRRC Report envisioned a "long-range sustained effort -- both public and private" to achieve the goals fixed for the nation in the outdoors. While recognizing the need for acquiring additional parklands, ORRRC stressed making more effective use of resources already available but overly restricted or not used at all for recreation. The commission also presented a strong case for providing natural, or open, areas in the first- step planning of the new communities that the expanding population would require.
The acceptance of the ORRRC recommendations was extraordinary. In the months following their presentation a number were put into effect by legislative action or administrative ruling. A new Bureau of Outdoor Recreation and a cabinet-level Federal Recreation Council was established, with the Bureau carrying forward many of the specific program recommendations.
Most significant, perhaps, was that the ORRRC Report engendered a new enthusiasm and awareness for conservation and outdoor recreation. Citing the commission's recommendations, state and local governments initiated new programs.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the creation, implementation, and general activities of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission from 1949-1964 with the bulk of the material dated between 1958 and 1963. The collection consists primarily of background material relating to members of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, as well as correspondence between Laurance Rockefeller and his advisors, reports, studies, and speeches given by Laurance Rockefeller and others.
Arrangement
The Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission papers have been arranged into ten series to represent a simplified version of its original organization structure:
Series 1: Administrative Records; Series 2: Advisors, Representatives, and Staff Members; Series 3: Contracts and Financial Materials; Series 4: Geographical Areas; Series 5: Government Relations Series 6: Reports and Studies; Series 7: Laurance S. Rockefeller; Series 8: General Files; Series 9: Meetings; Series 10: Clippings
Separated Materials
Special format items have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Outdoor recreation; National parks and reserves -- Planning; Wilderness areas -- Recreational use; Federal aid to outdoor recreation; Recreation and state
- Administrative Records, 1958-1962; 1; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of biographical and organizational information about the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission and is largely made up of background papers, bylaws, manuals, and policies.
  - Act Establishing the ORRRC, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Assisting Organizations, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Background Data, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Bylaws and Rules of Procedure, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronology, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jurisdiction Matters, 1959 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Legislative History, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Manual, 1959 July (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Office Procedures, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Organization, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs (Swearing in, personnel, etc.), 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Policy Memos (Gustafson file), undated (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
- Advisors, Representatives, and Staff Members, 1958-1964; 2; 2.66 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes
  This series contains correspondence between Laurance Rockefeller and key members of the Commission.
  Arrangement
  This series is divided into four subseries: Commissioners and Representatives; Advisory Council; Academic Consultants; and Staff Members.
  - Commissioners and Representatives, 1958-1962; 1
    - Commission Members - List, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Commissioners - Form Letters to, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Executive Committee Members, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Anderson, Senator Clinton P., 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Collier, Representative Harold R., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Dana, Samuel T., 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Dryfoos, Mrs. Orvile E., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Dryfoos, Mrs. Orvile E., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted from access - contains personnel materials
    - Dworshak, Senator Henry C., 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Jackson, Senator Henry M., 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Kyl, Representative John, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Lee, Mrs. Halfdan, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Martin, Senator Thomas E., 1959 September-December (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Miller, Senator Jack, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Neuberger, Senator Richard L., 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Orell, Bernard L., 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Penfold, Joseph W., 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Pfost, Representative Gracie, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Rivers, Representative Ralph J., 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Saylor, Representative John P., 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - State Representatives, 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Smith, Fred, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Ulman, Representative Al, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Wilson, Chester S., 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Advisory Council, 1958-1962; 2
    - Albright, Horace M., 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
    - Banks, Harvey O., 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Bassemeyer, James L., 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Broome, Harvey, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Brownfield A.D., Senior, 1960 January 19 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Canham, Erwin D., 1961 May (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Chorley, Kenneth, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Christensen, Mrs. Harold, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Collins, LeRoy, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Duffy, Ward E., 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Francis, David L., 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Federal Liaison Officers, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 51-52)
    - Gabrielson, Ira N., 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - General, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Gulick, Luther, 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Hobby, Oveta Culp, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - McCaffrey, J.E., 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Membership Lists, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Minutes and Memos, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Nelson, DeWitt, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Nominations, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Partian, Lloyd E., 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Prendergast, Joseph, 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Shepard, David A., 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - White, Gilbert, 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Academic Consultants, 1959-1962; 3
    - Brumstead, Harlan B., 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Clawson, Marion, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Craighead, Frank, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Gallup, George, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Moos, Malcolm, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Nash, Jay B., 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Pough, Richard H., 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Rourke, Francis E., 1961 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Whyte, William H. Jr., 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Staff Members, 1958-1964; 4
    - Davis, Arthur, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Davis, Hugh, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Deputy Director for Studies - Candidates, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Diamond, Henry, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Employment Applications, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 80-81)
    - Executive Secretary - Candidates, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 82-83)
    - Kennedy, John R., 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Personnel Files, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Phillips, Rose G., 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Sargent, Francis W., 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 87-88)
      Contains still image.
    - Stevens, Lawrence N., 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Wengert, Norman I., 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 90)
- Contracts and Financial Material, 1959-1963; 3; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  This series contains correspondence relating to various contracts and expenses, as well as budget information and appropriation planning.
  - Appropriation Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Appropriation Estimates, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Contracts, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 94-95)
  - Contracts, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Contracts - Galaxy Inc., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Expenses, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 99)
- Geographical Areas, 1958-1962; 4; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  This series consists of proposals, pamphlets, and correspondence related to different areas of interest to the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission.
  Alphabetically by region.
  - Alaska, 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 100-101)
  - Alagash Region, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - California, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Cape Cod National Seashore, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historic Parks, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Colorado, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Connecticut, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Dinosaur National Park, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Echo Park Dam, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Florida, 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Grand Cayon, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Great Basin National Park, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Hawaii, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Indiana Dunes, 1959-1962 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Lake Tahoe, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Maine, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Massachusetts, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Missouri River Basin, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Mount Rainier, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - New York, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Oklahoma, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Oregon, 1962 July 13 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Prairie Regions, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Rainbow Ridge, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Vermont, 1961 April 10 (Box 11, Folder 126)
- Government Relations, 1951-1962; 5; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  This series is primarily contains correspondence between Laurance Rockefeller and various government officials. There is also a large amount of material on Congressional references to the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission as well as information pertaining to the Wilderness Act of 1964.
  - Agriculture, Department of, 1958-1962 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - American Federation of Labor - CIO, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Census Bureau, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Civil and Defense Mobilization Office, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Civil Service Commission, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Commerce, Department of, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - Comptroller General's Office, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - Congress - Bills (House and Senate), 1958-1962 (Box 12, Folder 134-135)
  - Congress - Correspondence and Memos, 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Congressional Record - References to ORRRC, 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Defense, Department of, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Engineers, U.S. Army - Corps of, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - Federal Highway Administration, 1958 December (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - Federal Inter-Agency - Committee on Recreation, 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Federal Power Commission, 1951-1962 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Governors of the U.S., 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Housing and Home Financing Agency, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Interior, Department of, 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Interior, Department of - Appropriation Hearings, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Interior and Insular Affairs Committee, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1961 January 24 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Justice, Department of, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Labor, Department of, 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Land Management, Bureau of, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - Mayors, Principal U.S. Cities, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - National Science Foundation, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - Senate - Interior Affairs: Wilderness Act, 1961 February 27 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Small Business Administration, 1961 January-February (Box 13, Folder 156)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1961 February 23 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - State, Department of, 1961 June (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - State, Inter-Agency Committee on Recreation, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Udall, Stewart L. - Secretary of the Interior, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 160)
  - Treasury, Department of, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 161)
  - Veterans Administration, 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 162)
- Reports and Studies, 1949-1696; 6; 3.61 Cubic Feet 9 letter document boxes and 1 half-letter document box
  This series contains a variety of reports and studies that were either conducted by the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission or used by the Commission for reference purposes. Most notably, this series contains the final report of Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission that was presented to President John F. Kennedy titled, "Outdoor Recreation for America," as well as the 27 volume series of reports that that were published by the Commission in 1962.
  - Action for Outdoor Recreation for America: A Digest of Report of the ORRRC, with Suggestions for Citizen Action, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 332)
  - Adirondack Mountains National Park, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 333)
  - Awards Programs for Beautification in the United States, 1968 February (Box 35, Folder 334)
  - Conservation in the Eastern Caribbean - Proceedings of the First Eastern Caribbean Conservation Conference, 1965 October 1-4 (Box 35, Folder 335)
  - Foreign Studies, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - Forms, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - The Hudson - Report of the Hudson River Valley Commission, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 336)
  - Information and Progress Reports, 1958-1962 (Box 14, Folder 165)
  - Interim Report, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 166)
  - Mailing Lists, 1961-1963 (Box 14, Folder 167)
  - National Recreation Survey, 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 168)
  - Outdoor Action for Outdoor Recreation, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 337)
  - Outdoor Recreation for America: a report to the President and to Congress, 1962; 2016:FA787:001 (Box 35, Folder 338)
    Separated Materials
    Special format items have been separated from the above listed file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - Outdoor Recreation for America (ORFA) - Comments (U.S.), 1962 (Box 14, Folder 169-170)
  - Outdoor Recreation for America (ORFA) - Comments (Foreign), 1962 (Box 14, Folder 171)
  - Outdoor Recreation for America (ORFA) - Materials, 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 172)
  - Participation Studies, 1961 May 8 (Box 14, Folder 173)
  - Photographs, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 174)
    Contains still images.
  - Production and Distribution - Martin, Donald N. and Co., undated (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Production and Distribution - Printing, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - Project Authorization, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 177-178)
  - Progress Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Proposed Administrative Organization for the Extended Park and Recreation Program of New York State, American Conservation Association, Inc., 1967 February 6 (Box 35, Folder 339)
  - Report to the President and to the President's Council on Environmental Quality, Citzen Advisory Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 35, Folder 340)
  - Report to the President, White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 May 24-25 (Box 35, Folder 341)
  - Questionnaires, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Recommendations and Lists of Studies, undated (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Recreation and Scenic Aspects - St. Lawrence Project (NYS Council of Parks), 1949 January (Box 15, Folder 182)
  - Special Studies Group - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF), 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 183)
  - Staff Projects, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 184)
  - Staff Summary Report, 1961 July 5 (Box 15, Folder 185)
  - Study Plans, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 186, Box 16, Folder 187)
  - Study Report 1: Public Outdoor Recreation Areas - Acreage, Use, Potential, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 342)
  - Study Report 2: List of Public Outdoor Recreation Areas 1960, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 343)
  - Study Report 3: Wilderness and Recreation - A Report on Resources, Values and Problems, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 344-345)
  - Study Report 4: Shoreline Recreation Resources of the United States, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 346)
  - Study Report 5: The Quality of Outdoor Recreation: as Evidenced by User Satisfaction, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 347)
  - Study Report 6: Hunting in the United States - Its Present and Future Role, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 348)
  - Study Report 7: Sport Fishing - Today and Tomorrow, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 349)
  - Study Report 8: Potential New Sites for Outdoor Recreation in the Northeast, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 350)
  - Study Report 9: Alaska Outdoor Recreation Potential, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 351)
  - Study Report 10: Water for Recreation - Values and Opportunities, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 352)
  - Study Report 11: Private Outdoor Recreation Facilities, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 353)
  - Study Report 12: Paying for Recreation Facilities, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 354)
  - Study Report 13: Federal Agencies and Outdoor Recreation, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 355)
  - Study Report 14: Directory of State Outdoor Recreation Administration, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 356)
  - Study Report 15: Open Space Action, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 357)
  - Study Report 16: Land Acquisition for Outdoor Recreation - Analysis of Selected Legal Problems, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 358)
  - Study Report 17: Multiple Use of Land and Water Areas, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 359)
  - Study Report 18: A Look Abroad - the Effect of Foreign Travel on Domestic Outdoor Recreation and a Brief Survey of Outdoor Recreation in Six Countries, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 360)
  - Study Report 19: National Recreation Survey, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 361-362)
  - Study Report 20: Participation in Outdoor Recreation - Factors Affecting Demand among American Adults, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 363)
  - Study Report 21 Volume 1: The Future of Outdoor Recreation in the Metropolitan Regions of the United States - The National View - Present Conditions and Future Prospects of Outdoor Recreation for Residents of the Metropolitan Centers of Atlanta, St. Louis and Chicago, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 364-365)
  - Study Report 21 Volume 2: The Future of Outdoor Recreation in the Metropolitan Regions of the United States - the Impact of the Growth of the Los Angeles Metropolitan Region on the Demand for Outdoor Recreation Facilities in Southern California - 1976 and 2000, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 366)
  - Study Report 22: Trends in American Living and Outdoor Recreation, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 367-368)
  - Study Report 23: Projections to the Years 1976 and 2000: Economic Growth, Population, Labor Force and Leisure, and Transportation, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 369-370)
  - Study Report 24: Economic Studies of Outdoor Recreation, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 371)
  - Study Report 25: Public Expenditures for Outdoor Recreation, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 372)
  - Study Report 26: Prospective Demand for Outdoor Recreation, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 373)
  - Study Report 27: Outdoor Recreation Literature - A Survey, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 374)
  - Summaries of Study Reports, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 188-189)
  - Work Plan for the National Forest Recreation Survey, 1959 June (Box 16, Folder 190)
  - Work Plan for the National Forest Recreation Survey, 1959 August (Box 16, Folder 191)
- Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1955-1962; 7; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  This series consists of correspondence, public relation material, and speeches given by Laurance Rockefeller during his involvement with the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission.
  - Correspondence - Congratulations, 1958-1962 (Box 16, Folder 192)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 193)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 194)
  - Inter-Office Memos, 1958-1962 (Box 17, Folder 195)
  - Pamphlets, 1955-1961 (Box 17, Folder 196)
  - Participation in Public Functions, 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - Speeches - Copies, 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 198-199)
  - Speeches - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 200-205)
  - Speeches - Drafts, undated (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Speeches - Other than by LSR, 1959-1962 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - Speeches - Reference Material, 1959-1962 (Box 19, Folder 208-212)
  - Speeches - Statement before the Special Subcommittee on Deficiencies, 1959 June 18 (Box 19, Folder 213)
- General Files, 1955-1962; 8; 3.51 Cubic Feet 8 letter document boxes and 1 legal document box
  The General Files series is the largest series within the collection. It covers areas of interest to the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission including various people, organizations, and subjects.
  Alphabetically
  - American Institute of Planners, 1960 October 26 (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - American Planning and Civic Association, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - American Political Science Association, 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 216)
  - Articles - Recreation, 1961-1962 (Box 20, Folder 217)
  - Aspinwall, Wayne N., 1960-1962 (Box 20, Folder 218)
  - Boating and Marine Affairs, 1959-1962 (Box 20, Folder 219)
  - Camping Affairs, 1959-1962 (Box 20, Folder 220)
  - CBS Radio TV, 1960-1962 (Box 20, Folder 221)
  - Charts, Graphs, and Plans, 1959-1962 (Box 20, Folder 222)
  - Cluster Developments, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 223)